准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
青虫
翻译: 1440kHz
导演
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  珊迪奇克斯要出远门了
Ah, Sandy Cheeks is going out of town
她临走前交代海绵宝宝和派大星
and has asked SpongeBob and Patrick
帮她照顾宠物
to do a little pet-sitting for her
照顾宠物
Pet-sitting?
坐
那样不会把宠物伤着吗
Won't that hurt them?
也许珊迪本来应该另外找人照顾
Perhaps she should have asked someone else
派大星  我都不知道你会说鸟语
Gee, Patrick, I didn't know you spoke bird
不对
No
那是意大利语  海绵宝宝
that's Italian, SpongeBob
好了各位  这边的是小鸟的食物
Okay, boys, this here's Birdy's food
一天要喂两次
Feed him twice a day
要喂一整袋
This whole sack?
不用  喂一杯就行
Naw, just a cup's worth
这个是我的蟋蟀
This here's my cricket
蟋蟀在向你们问好呢
He's saying hello to you
是不是很可爱啊
Ain't he cute?
抱歉  我不会意大利语
Sorry, I don't speak Italian
好  这个是小蛇
Okay, and this here's Snakey
肚子里肿起来那块是什么
What's that lump in his belly?
那是人家晚饭
Well, that's his dinner
行了  交代得够多了
Well, I guess that's it
我得走了
I got to go
几天过后再见
I'll see you fellers in a couple of days
再见  珊迪
Bye, Sandy
等等
Wait
你忘介绍这个宠物了
You forgot about this pet
那是我唯一养的小青虫
That's only Wormy
吃得不多
He don't eat much
快看小青虫  派大星
Look at him, Patrick
是不是很棒
Isn't he great?
嗨  小家伙
Hey, little fella
我挠我挠
Kitchy-kitchy koo-koo
快看  是不是很可爱啊
Look, isn't he just precious?
把小青虫带出去玩吧
Let's take him out to play
1,000
藏好了吗  我来找了
Ready or not, here I come
你找到我了
You found me
你在这啊
There you are
找到我们了
He found us
朋友之间就要至死不渝
A friend is a friend to the end of the end
一辈子到永远
That's forever and a day
待在你身边  我绝不与你分别
Stay by your side, won't hear me say goodbye
无论如何
come what may
朋友就该这样
'Cause that's what friends do
就该这样
That's what friends do
朋友就该这样
'Cause that's what friends do
就该这样
That's what friends do
朋友就该这样
'Cause that's what friends do
就该这样
That's what friends do
朋友就该这样
'Cause that's what friends do
海绵宝宝  我好不想过完今天
Gee, SpongeBob, I don't want today to end, ever
我知道  派大星
I know, Patrick
一生中像今天这样的日子
Days like today come once
可能就只有一两天
maybe twice in a lifetime
细细品味每一瞬间
Savor every moment
全都要感谢小青虫
And it's all thanks to Wormy
好朋友
我做了这个送给小青虫
I made this for Wormy--
我们的新好朋友
our new best friend
明天再见  新好朋友
Until tomorrow, new best friend
别难过  小家伙
Don't be sad, little buddy
明天我们一回来马上跟你嬉戏玩耍
We'll be back first thing in the morning
for frolic and fun
为何太阳一定要在这美好的一天落下
Why must the sun set on this perfect day?
好好睡吧  小青虫
Sleep well, Wormy
别难过了  派大星
Don't be sad, Patrick
明天就能再见面了
It's only until tomorrow
我来了  小青虫
Here I come, Wormy
我也是
Me, too
然后就要玩抓人游戏
And, and then we're going to play tag
然后就要涂颜色
and then we're going to color
然后搭一座纸牌屋
and then we're build a house of cards
我们回来了  小青虫
We're back, Wormy
小青虫
Wormy
Wormy?
小青虫哪去了
Where's Wormy?
那什么东西
What's that thing?
本来应该在里面啊
He's got to be in here
小青虫很有可能出事了
I think something bad happened to Wormy
好朋友
还把好朋友绶带落下了
He left his Best Friend ribbon behind
那什么东西
What is that thing?
不知道  派大星
I don't know, Patrick
但不管它是什么
But whatever it is
肯定已经把小青虫吃掉了
it must have eaten Wormy
我怎么老是会出这种事
Why does this keep happening to me?
快  派大星
Quick, Patrick
赶紧往大门逃跑
we got to make a run for the door
不
No
派大星  它把我们唯一出口堵上了
Patrick, he's blocking our only exit
又怎么了
Now what?
我们被困在这了
We're trapped in here
跟那个  那个
with that, that
吃好朋友的一起
best friend eater
别怕
Let's not panic
只要团结一致
We just have to stick together
记住  我们是二打一
Remember, it's two against one
对吧  派大星
Right, Patrick?
派大星
Patrick?
它把派大星吃了
He's eaten Patrick
派大星  你还活着
Patrick, you're alive
有吗
I am?
派大星  我们不能
Patrick, we can't just
把这只可怕怪物留在珊迪家
leave this horrible monster in Sandy's house
很有可能会吃掉珊迪其他宠物
It might eat Sandy's other pets
或者更惨烈  吃掉珊迪的宠物
Or worse, it might eat Sandy's pets
不  有可能会吃掉珊迪
No, it might eat Sandy
一定要把它赶出去
We got to get it out of here
是打给你的
It's for you
起效了
It's working
它要接电话了
He's going to answer it
真该死
Tartar sauce
你样子特别让人有食欲  派大星
You look pretty appetizing, Patrick
现在趴在上面等怪物过来
Now, just stay here and wait for the monster
我去拿网来
I'll go get the net
海绵宝宝  网拿快点
SpongeBob, hurry up with that net
珊迪
再等一下  派大星
Hold on, Patrick
我真没那么好吃  怪物先生
I really don't taste that good, Mr. Monster
我过来了  派大星
I'm coming, Patrick
不要  怪物先生
No, Mr. Monster
求你别吃我  不要
please don't eat me, no
饶了我吧  我不好吃
Spare me, I don't taste good
不要  求求你
No, please
等一下
Wait a second
好
Yeah
成功了  派大星
We did it, Patrick
珊迪会为我们骄傲的
Sandy's going to be so proud of us
我们把可怕的怪物赶出她家了
We got that horrible monster out of her house
最好的一点就是  她宠物都安全了
And best of all her pets are safe
因为可怕怪物现在
'cause that horrible creature is now
直奔着蟹堡王过去了
heading straight for the Krusty Krab
它要进大门
It's going in the front
蟹堡王
我们走秘密入口
Let's use the secret entrance
好  不要动
Okay, hold still
它要吃了章鱼哥跟蟹老板
It's going to eat Squidward and Mr. Krabs
快卧倒  蟹老板
Hit the deck, Mr. Krabs
说  钱
Say "money"
钱
Money
你这是什么意思  海绵宝宝
What's the meaning of this, SpongeBob?
情况现在特危险
We're in serious danger
有个  有
There's a, a
有个怪物在外面
a monster out there
是会花钱的客人吗
Is he a paying customer?
不对  蟹老板
Oh, no, Mr. Krabs
它不吃蟹黄堡
It doesn't want to eat Krabby Patties
只吃你
It wants to eat you
就跟吃了小青虫一个样
Just like it ate Wormy
小青虫
Wormy?
为什么  为什么
Why, why?
年纪轻轻的
He was so young
我们忘不了你  小青虫
We'll never forget you, Wormy
既然白痴小剧场演完了
Well, if Moron Theater's over
我就来看一眼这个怪物的真面目
I think I'll just take a look at this monster
怪物就那个
That's the monster?
是不是很可怕
Pretty scary, huh?
活生生的噩梦
A living nightmare
早该知道的
I should have known
就这样了
Well, that's it
我要从狂人快船上下去了
I'm getting off the Loonie Express
这样的生物你们没见过
Now, just because you swabs
never seen a creature like this
不代表它就危险了
doesn't mean it's dangerous
我们尽力警告他们了
We tried to warn them
我不敢看
I can't watch
来看看这只可怕怪物
Get a load of the scary monster
怪物
Monster
看着就人畜无害
It looks harmless
还有点可爱
It's kind of cute
让我想到了钱
It reminds me of money
怪物
Monster
章鱼哥
Squidward?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
怪物把他们吃掉了
It ate them
怪物还走了
And there it goes
先是小青虫
First Wormy
然后章鱼哥  蟹老板
then Squidward, Mr. Krabs
那只到处飞的怪物
That flying monster
已经吃掉我们三个朋友了
has eaten three friends too many
必须告知居民们
We must inform the citizens
邪恶势力浮现出来了
Evil has surfaced
裤头村的命运
The fate of Bikini Bottom
就掌握在我们手里  派大星
is in our hands, Patrick
我们出发吧
Now, let's roll
遵命船长
Aye-aye, captain
好  派大星
Okay, Patrick
现在这个局面特别棘手
this is a very delicate situation
一定要特别小心处理才行
and must be treated with great care and sensitivity
明白
Gotcha
大家都快跑啊
Run, everybody, run
有怪物逃出来了
Monster on the loose
怪物
Monster
当心
裤头村的居民们请注意
Attention, Bikini Bottom
有只到处飞的怪物要吃了你们
There's a flying monster that's going to eat you
裤头村新闻
注意  注意
Attention, attention
刚刚收到的消息
This just in
一只巨大怪物正在袭击裤头村
A giant monster is attacking Bikini Bottom
我的腿
My leg
成功了  派大星
We did it, Patrick
我们拯救了裤头村
We saved the city
想想要是我们没跟大家交代怪物的事
Just think what might have happened
裤头村会有什么后果
if we didn't tell everyone about the monster
交代什么来着
About the what?
停
行
裤头村
公交站
真见鬼
Shoot
好像有龙卷风刮过这里了
Looks like a twister hit this place
大家都去哪了
Where is everybody?
你好啊  小青虫
Hi there, Wormy
你应该得等我回来才变蝴蝶的
You weren't supposed to change till I got back
这样应该就能装起来了  小家伙
That ought to hold you, little guy
你好啊  海绵宝宝
Howdy, SpongeBob
珊迪抓到怪物了
Sandy caught the monster
我都不知道大家原来特别想念我
I didn't know I'd been missed so much
天啊
Golly
看来我得多出几次远门
Maybe I should go out of town more often
彩色汉堡
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
已经36天没客人了
36 days without a customer
好
So
饿
hungry
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
有客人
A customer
没吃的
No food
三天了
three days
请你稍等一下
Hold on, me bucko
吃的马上就来
Food's on the way
你身上有钱  对吧
You got money, right?
对
Yeah
海绵宝宝  给他上吃的
SpongeBob, bring this man some grub
趁他还没晕倒
before he keels over
吃的来了  先生
Here you go, sir
蟹黄堡是吧
Krabby Patties, huh?
全海底最好
Finest under the sea
对对  没错
Yeah, yeah, sure
可活力又在哪
but where's the pizzazz?
看看这地方
Look at this place
究竟有什么主题
I mean, what is the theme here?
水下主题吗
Underwater?
无聊透顶
It's boring
吃的
Food
水
water
气氛
atmosphere
没人会来餐厅要气氛
Nobody goes to a restaurant for atmosphere
要的都是吃的
They go for food
汤姆
Hey, Tom
弗雷德
Fred
你要去蟹堡王吃饭吗
You want to eat at the Krusty Krab?
才不要  去贝壳小屋吧
Nah, let's go to the Shell Shack
他们那边有会说话的狗
They've got a talking dog
好啊
Great
话说狗是什么
Say, what's a dog?
我钱长脚走了
Money walking
必须想出那样的促销手段
I need to think up a gimmick like that
把客人引回来
to get people back in here
我有个点子
I have an idea
等等  我有个点子
Wait, I've got an idea
所以  女士们先生们
And so ladies and gentlemen
请大家多多购买蟹黄堡
make sure you buy lots of Krabby Patties
在此期间我要活埋自己
as I bury myself alive
加油加油加油
Go, go, go
不提供免费续杯
No free refills
大家都听我说
Hey, everyone, listen
贝壳小屋那条会说话的狗唱歌了
The talking dog at the Shell Shack is singing
走了
Come on
蟹老板  我有个点子
Mr. Krabs, I have an idea
我该怎么办
What am I going to do?
要是找不到好点子
If I don't find an idea
我就要停业了
I'll go out of business
蟹老板  我有个点子
Mr. Krabs, I have an idea
为什么就没人能给我个好点子
Why can't someone give me an idea?
蟹老板  我有个点子
Mr. Krabs, I have an idea
我的海神王啊  我可需要点子了
Great Neptune in heaven, I need an idea
蟹老板  我有个点子
Mr. Krabs, I have an idea
那你还在等什么  小子
What in the name of money are you waiting for, boy?
快告诉我
Tell me
好的蟹老板  做好准备
Okay, Mr. Krabs, prepare yourself
可以不用坐下
Don't bother sitting down
因为你看到这个一定会起立
because you'll just stand up when you see this
哒哒
Ta-da
我的大堡礁啊
Great Barrier Reef
这蟹黄堡馊了
That patty's spoiled
蟹老板  那不是腐坏的肉
Mr. Krabs, it's not tainted meat
是涂了颜料的肉
it's painted meat
彩色汉堡  六种设计师色彩均可购买
Pretty Patties, available in six designer colors
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward
过来看看
Come look
是不是看着就很有食欲
Don't that look appetizing?
可想吃了
Good, sir
等下
Wait
给我来个多加紫色的橙色汉堡
Give me an orange patty with extra purple
然后还有啥  亮片奶昔
What's next, sequined milkshakes?
蝴蝶结薯条
Bow-tie french fries?
不
No
彩色汉堡  彩色汉堡
Pretty Patties, Pretty Patties
别唱了
Stop it
这肯定是好点子
I know this is a good idea
给你们瞧
I'll show you
我  我
I'll, I'll
我要自己开餐厅
I'll open my own restaurant
等着瞧
You'll see
派大星  你也生气吗
Hey, Patrick, are you angry, too?
对
Yeah
怎么了
What's the matter?
我看不到我额头
I can't see my forehead
你有什么问题
What's your problem?
我有个好点子  别人都不认可
I have a good idea and no one else thinks so
同感
Me, too
充气裤子
Inflatable pants
你点子是什么
What's your idea?
我要开一家餐厅
I'm going to open up a restaurant
卖彩色汉堡
and sell Pretty Patties
别管我馊点子了
Forget my dumb idea
你那点子好
That's great
准备好迎接客流高峰了吗  派大星
Are you ready for the big rush, Patrick?
马上就会有不少饿肚子客人大排长龙
Pretty soon those hungry customers will be lining up
因为我们开业了
because we are open
开
我准备好了
I'm ready
逝者安息
我准备好了
此处付款          彩色汉堡
派大星  我们坐这多久了
Patrick, how long have we been sitting here?
我得再画个新电池装进去
I got to draw a new battery for this
万一蟹老板说得对呢
What if Mr. Krabs was right?
我的点子可能确实太傻了
Maybe my idea is dumb
海绵宝宝  有时候我们必须深入内心
SpongeBob, sometimes we have to go
deep inside ourselves
才能解决问题
to solve our problems
我好怕
I'm scared
那我来帮你深入
Then I'm going in for you
抱歉
Sorry
充气裤子太白痴
stupid inflatable pants
有什么发现吗
Did you find anything?
你们这边卖吃的吗
Do you sell food here?
没错
Yes, sir
我们在卖彩色汉堡
We sell Pretty Patties
这玩意都发绿了
That thing's green
绿了
Green
蟹老板说得对
Mr. Krabs was right
这些我该怎么办
What am I going to do with all these?
这个是紫色的吗
Is that one purple?
紫色可是我最爱的颜色
Purple is my favorite color
还不错
This isn't half bad
世界听我说
Hey, world
彩色汉堡就是史上最强点子
Pretty Patties is the best idea ever
瑞克  你怎么能这样
Oh, Rick, how could you?
你我一体同心
You and I, together we were one
已经是过去的事了
That was before
现在
But now
我要分手了
I'm splitting us up
我们打断这个节目
We interrupt this program
裤头村新闻
插播一则重大新闻
for an important news announcement
我身后这一大群狂热分子
This wild throng behind me
正在为裤头村的全新美食欢呼尖叫
is screaming for Bikini Bottom's
newest culinary sensation
一起来听听看
Let's take a listen
彩色汉堡
Pretty Patties
Pretty Patties?
不难看出  彩色汉堡十分火爆
It's easy to see that Pretty Patties are popular
可彩色汉堡究竟有什么魅力
But just what is it about them
让裤头村的食客们这般狂野
that drives Bikini Bottom feeders wild?
它们很搭我们的包包
They match our purses
它们让我想起了家乡
They remind me of home
彩色汉堡好
Pretty Patties rule
海绵宝宝先生
Mr. SquarePants
你是如何走向成功的
how do you explain all this success?
不知道
I don't know
这么笨一个点子怎么就赚得到钱了
How can you make money with such a stupid idea?
这么强一个点子怎么就赚不到钱了
And how can you not make money
with such a brilliant idea?
起先我们不知道要怎么处理那么多钱
At first we didn't know what to do with all the money
我们试过把钱埋了
We tried burying it
把钱撕了
shredding it
把钱烧了
and burning it
最后我们决定把钱送出去
But in the end, we decided to just give it all away
免费送钱
欢迎下次再来
Come again, sir
我这就再排一次队
I'm getting back in line
不敢相信
I don't believe it
一定要亲眼去看看
I got to see this for meself
小心点  兄弟
Watch it, buddy
我不稀罕你有多想吃彩色汉堡
I don't care how much you want your Pretty Patty
反正你都得跟我们一样排队
You're going to have wait in line like the rest of us
我从来没人来这排队
I never had a line
服务号数
谁是46853号
Who's number 46,853?
我从来没有46853个客人
I never had 46,853 customers
餐给你  先生
Here you go, sir
一定要色彩缤纷
You stay pretty
很好
All right
蟹老板  是你吗
Mr. Krabs, is that you?
是不是很棒啊  蟹老板
Isn't this great, Mr. Krabs
彩色汉堡太火了
The pretty patties are a big hit
确实挺火  小子
They sure are, boy
你表现十分出色
You're doing pretty well for yourself
估计你已经把蟹堡王抛在脑后了吧
I guess you've completely forgotten the Krusty Krab
没有  从来没忘
No, sir, I haven't
其实有时候
In fact, sometimes
我真的特想念蟹堡王的往日时光
I really miss the old days at the Krusty Krab
你肯定也很想念章鱼哥
I bet you miss Squidward
还有烤架
and the grill
还有瞭望台
and the crow's nest
对  对
Yeah, yeah
知道我最想念什么不  蟹老板
And you know what I miss the most, Mr. Krabs?
拿两片腌椰菜摩擦
That tiny squeaky sound you get
发出来的小小的吱吱声
when you rub two pickles together
懂我意思吗  蟹老板
You know what I mean, Mr. Krabs?
对
Yeah
Yes
我都懂  小子
yes, I do, lad
蟹堡王只要走一小段路就能到了
Well, the Krusty Krab is only a short walk away
看在老交情份上  你就去看看吧
Why don't you head on down for old times' sake?
我还不能走  蟹老板
I can't leave, Mr. Krabs
摊子怎么办
What about the stand?
你放心  小子
Don't worry, lad
摊子我来帮你照看
I'll watch the stand for ye
真的吗
You will?
不
No
我有更好的点子
I've got a better idea
你这个路边摊直接归我管
I'll take this old roadside stand
off your hands for keeps
作为交换
And in exchange
我把蟹堡王交给你
I'll give you the Krusty Krab
有章鱼哥  有烤架
with Squidward, the grill
还有吱吱叫的腌椰菜
and all those squeaky pickles
你说什么  蟹老板
What did you say, Mr. Krabs?
这是蟹堡王的钥匙
Here's the key to the Krusty Krab
她现在是你的了
She's yours now
谢谢
Thank you
现在我该干啥  蟹老板
What should I do now, Mr. Krabs?
跑过去  小子
Run to her, boy
她就在等着你呢
She's waiting for ya
我腿麻了  蟹老板
I can't feel my legs, Mr. Krabs
小子你放心  我来解决
Don't worry, lad, I'll fix it
马上帮这位去蟹堡王
Get this to the Krusty Krab on the double
祝你好运  小子
Good luck, lad
美梦成真了
Dreams do come true
蟹堡王
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
现在由我为大家售卖彩色汉堡
Pretty Patties is now under new management
下一个是谁
Who's next?
是我
I am
这边
Over here
我准备好了
I'm ready
要赚大钱
for me money
欢迎购买彩色汉堡
Welcome to Pretty Patties
要我收你钱吗
May I take your money?
给我们退钱  老螃蟹
We want a refund, Krabs
谁
Who
怎么
how
什么
what?
你的破烂彩色汉堡害我脸变紫了
Your dumb Pretty Patties turned my face purple
看我苏格兰短裙里面成什么样了
Look what I got under my kilt
你看我们的舌头
And look at our tongues
你这是怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我们要退钱
We want our money back
退给我们46853个客人
All 46,853 of us
他跑哪去了
Where did he go?
抓住他
Get him
钥匙
My key
我钥匙哪去了
Where's my key?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  放我进去
SpongeBob, let me in
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  放我进去
SpongeBob, let me in
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob